niit-tech.com 2015-03-18

# Privacy Statement | NIIT Technologies

All contents are Copyright © 2007 NIIT Technologies. All rights reserved. No portion of this Privacy Statement may be copied/ reproduced in any form, or by any means without the prior written approval from NIIT Technologies Ltd.

 ** Contents**

1\. Introduction   
2\. NIIT Technologies' Principles to Protect Privacy

The following terms and conditions apply to all visitors, or users of this Web Site. By accessing this Web Site, the user acknowledges acceptance of these terms and conditions.

 ** 1\. Introduction**

NIIT Technologies Limited ("NIIT Technologies") is committed to respecting your privacy and distinguishes your need for appropriate safety of any personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with NIIT Technologies. NIIT Technologies has created privacy policy under the Indian IT Act, 2000, Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 (hereinafter referred to as Data Privacy Rules) in order to demonstrate its commitment to privacy. Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, addresses including an e-mail address or other contact details.  The authenticity of the personal information is the sole responsibility of the provider and that NIIT Technologies shall not be held accountable for the same.

In general, you can visit NIIT Technologies' web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself. To track user’s session, we retain your IP address. We do not link IP address to anything personally identifiable i.e. the users will be anonymous. Your use of an NIIT Technologies Web site signifies your acceptance of the NIIT Technologies Privacy Statement.

NIIT Technologies strives to comply with applicable laws that are designed to protect your privacy.

Your Consent

By using this Web site, you consent to the terms of NIIT Technologies' Privacy Policy and to NIIT Technologies' processing of Personal Information for the purposes given above. There are times, however, when NIIT Technologies may need information from you, such as your name and address. When information is needed, NIIT Technologies will try (but is not obligated) to let you know at the time of collection, how it will use the personal information. Usually, the personal information NIIT Technologies collects is used only by it to respond to your inquiry, process an order or allow you to access specific account information. Occasionally, NIIT Technologies may make the e-mail addresses, of those who provide information, available to other reputable organizations whose products or services it thinks you may find interesting. In these cases, you will be offered an opportunity to limit access to your information. In case NIIT Technologies does not receive any response from you to limit the access of your information, it shall be deemed that you consent to such distribution of your Personal Information as mentioned above.

 ** 2\. NIIT Technologies' Principles to Protect Privacy **

In order to protect your privacy, NIIT Technologies has adopted the following principles   
a) Security   
b) Cookie/Tracking Technology   
c) Links to other websites   
d) Choice   
e) Notice   
f) Access/Accuracy

(a) Security   
Wherever your Personal Information may be held within NIIT Technologies, the company intends to take reasonable steps to protect it from unauthorized access or disclosure. This information is only used to fulfil your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner. This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and/or alteration of information under our control. The data resides behind a firewall with access restricted to authorized NIITians. NIIT Technologies does not link IP address to anything personally identifiable   
Spam emails or unsolicited bulk emails are a major concern and NIIT Technologies has taken reasonable measures to minimize the transmission and impact of spam emails in its environment. Only sufficient information is forwarded to the sender in case of identification of a spam email and it gets rejected by NIIT Technologies.

(b) Cookie/Tracking Technology   
The Site may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

(c) Links to Other Websites   
NIIT Technologies website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

(d) Choice   
You may choose whether or not to provide Personal Information to NIIT Technologies. The notice NIIT Technologies intends to provide at the point where it collects Personal Information on the Site, should help you to make this choice. If you choose not to provide the Personal Information we request, you can still visit most of NIIT Technologies' web sites, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you. If you chose to have a relationship with NIIT Technologies, such as a contractual or other business relationship, NIIT Technologies will naturally continue to contact you in connection with that business relationship. You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Indian IT Act, 2000, Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 (hereinafter referred to as Data Privacy Rules). If you would like a copy of the information held on you, please contact us at [privacy@niit-tech.com](mailto:privacy@niit-tech.com).

(e) Notice   
Where NIIT Technologies collects Personal Information on the Site, NIIT Technologies intends to post a purpose statement that explains why Personal Information will be collected and whether NIIT Technologies plans to share such Personal Information outside of NIIT Technologies or with those working on NIIT Technologies' behalf. Unless the transfer of Personal Information is legally required, NIIT Technologies does not intend to transfer Personal Information without your permission to third parties who are not bound to act on NIIT Technologies' behalf. As a global organization, the data collected may be transferred internationally throughout NIIT Technologies offices. We will share the information only with our employees & trusted partners. The personal information will be transferred if NIIT Technologies is acquired by, or merged with another company.

(f) Access/Accuracy   
To the extent that you do provide NIIT Technologies with Personal Information, NIIT Technologies wishes to maintain accurate Personal Information. Where NIIT Technologies collects Personal Information from you on the site, its aim is to provide a means of contacting NIIT Technologies should you need to update or correct that information. If for any reason, those means are unavailable or inaccessible, you may send updates and corrections about your Personal Information to [privacy@niit-tech.com](mailto:privacy@niit-tech.com), or to the grievance officer, and NIIT Technologies will make reasonable efforts to incorporate the changes.

If you have any questions/suggestions about NIIT Technologies Data Privacy Policy please e-mail us at [privacy@niit-tech.com](mailto:privacy@niit-tech.com).

(g) Grievance Redressal: As per rule 5(9) of the Data Privacy Rules, Colonel (Retd) AK Anand has been designated as Grievance Officer. The contact details of the officer are as below:   
E-mail id: [arun.anand@niit-tech.com](mailto:arun.anand@niit-tech.com)   
Phone: +91 120 381 5643

All the grievances and any discrepancies of the provider of information shall be redressed within one month (30 days) from the date of receipt of grievance.

NIIT Technologies reserves its right to change, modify or update this privacy policy at any time without notice.

(h) Opt Out Provision   
Please indicate if you desire to opt out of the provisions of this policy.

NIIT Technologies reserves its right to change, modify or update this privacy statement at any time without notice.
